[
  {
    "question": "Mladiček / Psiček",
    "answer": "Puppy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Morski prašiček",
    "answer": "Guinea pig"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hrček",
    "answer": "Hamster"
  },
  {
    "question": "Želva",
    "answer": "Turtle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kuščar",
    "answer": "Lizard"
  },
  {
    "question": "Podgana",
    "answer": "Rat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Opica",
    "answer": "Monkey"
  },
  {
    "question": "Miš / Miši",
    "answer": "Mouse / Mice"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mungos",
    "answer": "Mongoose"
  },
  {
    "question": "Zajec",
    "answer": "Rabbit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Piščanec",
    "answer": "Chick / Chicken"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pes",
    "answer": "Dog"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ovca",
    "answer": "Sheep"
  },
  {
    "question": "Krava",
    "answer": "Cow"
  },
  {
    "question": "Puran",
    "answer": "Turkey"
  },
  {
    "question": "Petelin",
    "answer": "Rooster / Cockerel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Konj",
    "answer": "Horse"
  },
  {
    "question": "Koza",
    "answer": "Goat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Raca / Račke",
    "answer": "Duck / Ducklings"
  },
  {
    "question": "Prašič",
    "answer": "Pig"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lastovka",
    "answer": "Swallow"
  },
  {
    "question": "Osel",
    "answer": "Donkey"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gos / Gosi",
    "answer": "Goose / Geese"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kokoš",
    "answer": "Hen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mačka",
    "answer": "Cat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pingvin",
    "answer": "Penguin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Veverica",
    "answer": "Squirrel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kenguru",
    "answer": "Kangaroo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Zebra",
    "answer": "Zebra"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kit",
    "answer": "Whale"
  },
  {
    "question": "Slon",
    "answer": "Elephant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tiger",
    "answer": "Tiger"
  },
  {
    "question": "Noj",
    "answer": "Ostrich"
  },
  {
    "question": "Riba",
    "answer": "Fish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Štorklja",
    "answer": "Stork"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lev",
    "answer": "Lion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Krokodil",
    "answer": "Crocodile"
  },
  {
    "question": "Povodni konj",
    "answer": "Hippo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Panda",
    "answer": "Panda"
  },
  {
    "question": "Žirafa",
    "answer": "Giraffe"
  },
  {
    "question": "Delfin",
    "answer": "Dolphin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Medved",
    "answer": "Bear"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lama",
    "answer": "Llama"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kača",
    "answer": "Snake"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pajek",
    "answer": "Spider"
  },
  {
    "question": "Labod",
    "answer": "Swan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Streha",
    "answer": "Roof"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gnezdo",
    "answer": "Nest"
  },
  {
    "question": "Travnik",
    "answer": "Meadow"
  },
  {
    "question": "Drevo",
    "answer": "Tree"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hlev",
    "answer": "Stable"
  },
  {
    "question": "Trava",
    "answer": "Grass"
  },
  {
    "question": "Blato",
    "answer": "Mud"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ribnik",
    "answer": "Pond"
  },
  {
    "question": "Lupina / Oklep",
    "answer": "Shell"
  },
  {
    "question": "Okel",
    "answer": "Tusk"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rog / Rogovi",
    "answer": "Horn / Horns"
  },
  {
    "question": "Krempelj",
    "answer": "Claw"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kljun",
    "answer": "Beak"
  },
  {
    "question": "Krilo",
    "answer": "Wing"
  },
  {
    "question": "Rep",
    "answer": "Tail"
  },
  {
    "question": "Plavut",
    "answer": "Fin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Škrge",
    "answer": "Gills"
  },
  {
    "question": "Luske",
    "answer": "Scales"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kopita",
    "answer": "Hoofs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Brki",
    "answer": "Whiskers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Surla / Rilec / Gobec",
    "answer": "Trunk / Snout"
  },
  {
    "question": "Griva",
    "answer": "Mane"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tačka",
    "answer": "Paw"
  },
  {
    "question": "Perje",
    "answer": "Feathers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Zabaven",
    "answer": "Funny"
  },
  {
    "question": "Len",
    "answer": "Lazy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Prijazen",
    "answer": "Friendly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dolgočasen",
    "answer": "Boring"
  },
  {
    "question": "Šibek",
    "answer": "Weak"
  },
  {
    "question": "Močan",
    "answer": "Strong"
  },
  {
    "question": "Marljiv",
    "answer": "Hard-working"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nevaren",
    "answer": "Dangerous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pogumen",
    "answer": "Brave"
  },
  {
    "question": "Divji",
    "answer": "Wild"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ukročen / Domač",
    "answer": "Tame"
  },
  {
    "question": "Tiho / Tih",
    "answer": "Quiet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sramožljiv",
    "answer": "Shy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hiter",
    "answer": "Fast"
  },
  {
    "question": "Velik",
    "answer": "Big"
  },
  {
    "question": "Visok",
    "answer": "Tall"
  },
  {
    "question": "Glasen",
    "answer": "Loud"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dajati volno",
    "answer": "To give wool"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dajati mleko",
    "answer": "To give milk"
  },
  {
    "question": "Čuvati hišo",
    "answer": "To guard the house"
  },
  {
    "question": "Delati nam družbo",
    "answer": "To keep company"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dajati jajca",
    "answer": "To give eggs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dajati meso",
    "answer": "To give meat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Plezati na drevesa",
    "answer": "To climb trees"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hitro teči",
    "answer": "To run fast"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kopati luknje",
    "answer": "To dig holes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Zbirati oreščke",
    "answer": "To collect nuts"
  },
  {
    "question": "Spati stoje",
    "answer": "To sleep on their feet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ravnati z živalmi s spoštovanjem",
    "answer": "To treat animals with respect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Konj je velik, hiter, visok in močan.",
    "answer": "A horse is big, fast, tall and strong."
  },
  {
    "question": "Krokodil je velik, divji, močan in nevaren.",
    "answer": "A crocodile is big, wild, strong and dangerous."
  },
  {
    "question": "Mačka je tiha, prijazna in lena.",
    "answer": "A cat is quiet, friendly and lazy."
  },
  {
    "question": "Zajec je majhen, šibek, hiter, tih, sramežljiv in prijazen.",
    "answer": "A rabbit is small, weak, fast, quiet, shy and friendly."
  },
  {
    "question": "Žirafa je zelo zanimiva žival.",
    "answer": "The giraffe is a very interesting animal."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ima dolg vrat, dolge noge in lise po telesu.",
    "answer": "It has a long neck, long legs and spots over its body."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ima dva rogova na vrhu glave in dolg kosmat jezik.",
    "answer": "It has two horns on the top of its head and a long hairy tongue."
  },
  {
    "question": "Pingvin ne more leteti, ampak lahko plava.",
    "answer": "A penguin can't fly but it can swim."
  },
  {
    "question": "Veverica ne more govoriti, ampak lahko zbira oreščke.",
    "answer": "A squirrel can't speak but it can collect nuts."
  },
  {
    "question": "Gos ne more skakati, ampak lahko leti.",
    "answer": "A goose can't jump but it can fly."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kenguru ne more plavati, ampak lahko skače.",
    "answer": "A kangaroo can't swim but it can jump."
  },
  {
    "question": "Zebra ne more skakati z drevesa na drevo, ampak lahko hitro teče.",
    "answer": "A zebra can't jump from tree to tree but it can run fast."
  },
  {
    "question": "Nekega dne najde kost.",
    "answer": "One day he finds a bone."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vzame jo v usta in jo želi odnesti domov.",
    "answer": "He puts it in his mouth and wants to take it home."
  },
  {
    "question": "Na poti domov prečka most.",
    "answer": "On the way home he crosses a bridge."
  },
  {
    "question": "Pogleda dol v vodo.",
    "answer": "He looks down into the water."
  },
  {
    "question": "Vidi psa z veliko kostjo.",
    "answer": "He sees a dog with a big bone."
  },
  {
    "question": "Prime po podobi v vodi.",
    "answer": "He snaps at the picture in the water."
  },
  {
    "question": "Ko odpre usta, izgubi svojo kost.",
    "answer": "When he opens his mouth, he loses his bone."
  },
  {
    "question": "Revni Snuffy ne ve, da vidi samega sebe v vodi.",
    "answer": "Poor Snuffy doesn't know he sees himself in the water."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kadar mačke ni doma, miši plešejo.",
    "answer": "When the cat's away the mice will play."
  },
  {
    "question": "Kokoši dajejo ljudem jajca in meso.",
    "answer": "Hens give eggs and meat to people."
  },
  {
    "question": "Pes čuva hišo in nam dela družbo.",
    "answer": "A dog guards the house and keeps us company."
  },
  {
    "question": "Krava daje ljudem mleko in meso.",
    "answer": "A cow gives milk and meat to people."
  },
  {
    "question": "Žirafe spijo stoje.",
    "answer": "Giraffes sleep on their feet."
  }
]
